(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
パレパレパレ 輝くんだよ
Parade, parade, parade, let's shine!
呼び合う声を合図に
With our voices calling out as the signal
パレパレパレ 探しにいく
Parade, parade, parade, let's go searching
スタートは何度だって
We can start over as many times as it takes
イェーイ！
Yay!
皆さんこんにちは！儒烏風亭らでん生誕祭2025！
Hello everyone! Juufuutei Raden's Birthday 2025!
Our Bright Parade
作詞・作曲・編曲：堀江晶太
Lyrics, Comp, Arr: Shota Horie
始まりました！盛り上がっていきましょう！
It's started! Let's get excited!
ただ 独り言綴った
Just writing down my monologues
ただ 始まりたくて走った
Just wanting to start, I ran
遠く 暗がりに灯った
Lit up in the distant darkness
それは 眩しすぎた名前
That was a name far too dazzling
それは 優しすぎる想いで
That's a memory far too kind
もっと 近づきたくて手を伸ばした
Reaching out, wanting to get closer
思いがけず結び合った
We unexpectedly became tied together
ほら 今 迷子は隣になった
Look, now the lost child is right beside me
パレパレパレ 輝くんだよ
Parade, parade, parade, let's shine!
悔しさも愛しさも連れておいで
Bring both the frustration and the affection
風 夢 羽 飛び立てるさ
Wind, dreams, wings, we can take flight
ささやかな祈りは光 終わりなき兆し
A modest prayer is light, an endless sign
君を見つけたこと 胸を張れるよ
I can be proud of having found you
#らでん生誕祭2025
#RadenBirthday2025
Our Bright Parade
さぁ これから
So, from now on
Our Bright Parade Parade
まだ 頼りない予感を
Still with an unreliable premonition
歌おう 恥ずかしくなんてないよ
Let's sing, it's nothing to be ashamed of
誰も 解けないミステリー
A mystery that no one can solve
いつか また会えるおまじない
A spell to meet again someday
あの日 ゼロに始まった ストーリー
A story that started at zero that day
数えきれない言の葉 数えるような想いじゃないさ
It's not a feeling like counting countless words
ほら 今 僕らを ひとつと呼ぼう
Look, now let's call us one
Parade Parade Parade 眩いなよ
Parade Parade Parade, be dazzling
赦しあえる 切な 夜は煌めく
Forgiving each other, the painful nights sparkle
雨晴れ枯れ 窓の外 空
Rain, clear, withered, the sky outside the window
ふさわしい 旅路とは 君と歩くことさ
The appropriate journey is walking with you
君と歩くことなんだ
It's about walking with you
「ただいま」を聞けば 「おかえり」って叫ぶよ
When I hear "I'm home", I'll shout "Welcome back"
当たり前じゃないか
Isn't it obvious?
Parade Parade Parade 輝くんだよ
Parade Parade Parade, shine on
暗がりを満たすのは 君だ 僕だ
The ones who fill the darkness are you and me
Parade Parade Parade 輝くんだよ
Parade Parade Parade, shine on
悔しさも 愛おしさも 連れておいで
Bring your regrets and your love with you
風 夢 羽根 飛び立てるさ
Wind, dreams, wings, we can fly
ささやかな 祈りは光 終わりなき予感
A modest prayer is light, an endless premonition
君と飛び込んでゆく 素敵な空へとさ
I'll dive in with you towards the wonderful sky
ここから これから Our Bright Parade Parade...
From here, from now on, Our Bright Parade Parade...
Our Bright Parade Parade...
はーい！ということで、始まりました！
Hi! And with that, it's begun!
儒烏風亭らでん生誕祭2025です！
Juufuutei Raden Birthday Celebration 2025!
皆さん楽しんでますかー？
Is everyone having fun?!
どうも、ホロライブDEV_IS ReGLOSSの、賑やかしネタ枠担当、
Hello, I'm the one in charge of the lively comedic role in hololive DEV_IS ReGLOSS,
儒烏風亭一門は前座見習い、儒烏風亭らでんでございます！こんばんは！
a Zenza apprentice of the Juufuutei school, Juufuutei Raden! Good evening!
本日は、えー、2月4日、私、儒烏風亭らでんの誕生日ということで、
Today is, uh, February 4th, my birthday, Juufuutei Raden.
誕生日を記念して、初めての生誕ライブやります！やったー！わーい！
So to celebrate my birthday, I'm doing my first-ever birthday live! Yay! Whoo!
えー、儒烏風亭らでん生誕祭2025、ここで出会ったのも何かのご縁ということで...
Uh, Juufuutei Raden Birthday Celebration 2025: Meeting here is also a stroke of fate...
本日のタグは、#らでん生誕祭2025、
Today's hashtag is #RadenBirthday2025,
#らでん生誕祭2025です。いっぱいポストしてくれると嬉しいです！
#RadenBirthday2025. I'd be happy if you post a lot!
あの、儒烏風亭らでんの「儒烏風亭」一発変換で出ないので、
Since Juufuutei in "Juufuutei Raden" doesn't come up with a single conversion,
あのシンプルに、#らでん生誕祭2025で。よろしくお願いします！
just simply #RadenBirthday2025. Please use that!
さぁ、ということで。1曲目お送りいたしましたのはReGLOSSでね、
Now then. The first song we performed as ReGLOSS
歌わせていただきました「Our Bright Parade」でした。みんな、どうでした？
was "Our Bright Parade". Everyone, how was it?
どうだったかな、みんな？あ、おおーって言ってくれてる。ありがとうございます！
How was it, everyone? Oh, you're saying "Ooh!". Thank you!
チャットでね、応援してくれてる人もね、見えてますよ。ありがとうございます！
I can see the people supporting me in the chat too. Thank you!
あ、マイタケをぐるぐるしてる人もね、いるっぽいですね。ありがとうございます！
Ah, it looks like there are people spinning Maitake mushrooms too. Thank you!
マイタケね、全然、あの、ぐるぐるしてまわしてもらって。ありがとうございます！
Maitake... please, go ahead and spin them around. Thank you!
やっぱ「Our Bright Parade」ね。こう、最初の、やっぱReGLOSSの5人で歌いたいなーっていうのとね、
As expected of "Our Bright Parade". I really wanted to sing it with the five members of ReGLOSS at the start,
やっぱここから、もうライブが始まっていくぞっていうね...
and it's like, "the live is starting from here"...
こっからパレード始まっていくぞっていう曲なのでね。ちょっと1発目にね、歌わせていただきました。ありがとうございます！
it's a song that says "the parade is starting from here". So I sang it as the first track. Thank you!
えー、今ReGLOSSの話がありましたが、今回のライブのテーマは「ここで出会ったのも何かのご縁」でございます。
Uh, I just mentioned ReGLOSS, but the theme of this live is "Meeting here is also a stroke of fate".
えー、本日の生誕ライブまでに1年と何ヶ月だ？活動してきて、
Uh, how many months has it been over a year leading up to today's birthday live?
もう色んな人との出会いがあって。で、色んなことさせてもらって。
I've met so many people and been allowed to do so many things during my activities.
で、そんな中で今の自分が有るので、まぁその感謝を伝えられるような、今までのね、こう活動の軌跡になるような、そんなライブを目指しました。
And because I am who I am now thanks to that, I aimed for a live that could convey that gratitude and serve as a trajectory of my activities so far.
もう、ゲストの方たーくさんね、いらっしゃいますので、お楽しみに！皆さん。
There are so many guests coming, so look forward to it, everyone!
ゲストパートは収録でございます！
The guest part is pre-recorded!
ということはソロパートはどうなるんじゃい？っていうお話し...
Which means, what will happen to the solo part? That's the question...
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
なんとですね、
And what's more...
なんと、なんと、今回はリアルタイムでアンケート取ります！
What's more, what's more, this time we'll be taking a poll in real time!
縁ということでね、縁にちなんで、
Since it's about 'connections,' in keeping with the theme,
歌う楽曲にちなんだアンケートを取ろうと思っております。
I'm thinking of taking a poll related to the song I'm about to sing.
アンケートがね、ポコンと出てきます。
A poll will pop up suddenly.
選択肢が2つあります。
There will be two options.
皆さんね、その2つの選択肢、うわ、どっちがいいかな？っていうのを悩んで、
Everyone, please think carefully about which of those two options you'd prefer,
いっぱい悩んで選んでください。
And make your choice after careful consideration.
次の曲が終わるまでに選んでください。
Please make your choice by the time the next song finishes.
この次の曲ですね。
That's this next song.
この次の曲が終わるまでに選んでください。
Please choose by the time this next song ends.
そのアンケートの結果次第でソロパートで披露する曲が変わりますよということで、
Depending on the result of that poll, the song I perform in my solo part will change!
早速、最初のアンケートはこちらでございます。デデーン！
So, without further ado, here is our first poll. Ta-da!
どちらの花を見に行く？ スミレの花 or ハスの花
Which flower will you go to see? Violet or Lotus
今、リアルタイムで見ていただいている方はチャット欄にね、出てきたと思います。
For those watching in real time, it should have appeared in the chat section.
どちらの花を見に行きますか？
Which flower will you go to see?
スミレの花、もしくはハスの花。
A violet or a lotus.
さあ、皆さま、お好きな方をお選びください。
Now, everyone, please choose your favorite.
もしかして、じゃあこの花を選んだら実はあの曲なんじゃないかなっていうね、
Maybe you'll think, "If I choose this flower, it might be that song"...
予想も含めてね、楽しんでいただけると嬉しいです。
I hope you enjoy it, including making your predictions.
では、早速ですが、次の曲にいきたいと思います。
Well then, let's move on to the next song right away.
ここでね、べらべら喋っててもあれなので、次の曲いきますよ。
If I keep blathering on here, it won't do, so let's get to the next song.
皆さま、準備はいいですか？はーい！
Is everyone ready? Yeah!
いきなりね、うん、ゲストのあの方が、え、登場するということで、
Right away... yes, that guest is going to make an appearance.
そんなこんなも何かのご縁。登場します。
That, too, is some kind of connection. They're coming on stage.
それではいきましょう。どうぞ！
Well then, let's get started. Here we go!
Contas haleia on sharluies
Animita portimai juri
Teclox ocnoles dinaoketing
Hapu amukil shalbeilhu
Yari lilale minasokcha
Divnale minasuriadia
Tishi dilas veda veticus
Tivovolash marofu ha akua
Contas haleia on sharluies
Animita portimai juri
Alovi atolustudia
Nonto kias turia
Contas haleia on sharluies
Animita portimai juri
Teclox ocnoles dinaoketing
Hapu aduguel shalbailhu
Estuadigalu biria
Paratos lumia dislavo
Kurusuini animajuri
Nemeras muo tulu
Tirilalu pipulu
Nontamulu
Farmui mirabe mutzerfu
Onomabu maniro ontarune
Lidowia sarame
Tecantomirania... a...
Havilasimia
Mimora shelonitzonia
...ti mwa ish moro fu o ra
Vi mo ra she ro ra ra
Kontos hare ryuya o shallrys
Animu mi ta po de ma hi chu ri
Siklo ob nog les ti no ke ti
Ap av yo ge ro shall be i ru
Moru ves tant morant kan to
Di mwa ish moro fu o ra
Di mwa ish moro fu o ra... hap-a-a-a-a...
はい、ということで！なんと今回、アキ先輩に来ていただきました！
Yes, so! Surprisingly, Aki-senpai is here with us!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
はーい！みんな、アローナ！
Hi! Everyone, Alona!
ホロライブ1期生の癒し系ハーフエルフ、アキロゼことアキ・ローゼンタールです！
The healing half-elf of Hololive 1st Gen, Aki Rose aka Aki Rosenthal!
ハロハロハロアローナ！
Haro-haro-haro-alona!
やったー！アキ先輩来ちゃったよー！
Yay! Aki-senpai actually came!
本日はお越しいただき誠にありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for coming today!
いやいやいや、こちらこそ！
No, no, thank you!
あー嬉しい、これ。
I'm so happy.
歌わせていただいた曲「シャルイース」、
The song we sang, "Shallrys",
アキ先輩のオリジナル曲を一緒に歌わせていただき、こんなことがあっていいのかなって。
being able to sing Aki-senpai's original song together... I was wondering if it's okay to be this lucky.
めちゃめちゃ興奮してる、どうしよう。
I'm so excited, what should I do?
らでんちゃんがね、いつもこのシャルイースを大好きだってデビューの時から言ってくれてて。
Raden-chan has been saying she loves "Shallrys" since her debut.
むしろアキロゼはすっごい嬉しかったんだよ！
Aki Rose was actually incredibly happy about that!
今日こうやって一緒に歌って、踊って。
So singing and dancing together like this today...
ダンスレッスンもね、一緒にしたし、すごい楽しかった！
We did dance lessons together too, it was so much fun!
むしろありがとうね！
Thank you, rather!
えー！こちらこそー、ええー。
Eh! No, thank you!
今回のライブタイトルね、「ここで出会ったのも何かのご縁」っていう感じでやらしてもらってるんですけど。
The title of this live is "Meeting here must be fate".
やっぱこの曲がなければ、私、もしかしたらホロライブ知らなかった世界線もあって。
If it wasn't for this song, there might have been a timeline where I didn't know Hololive.
えー？！そうなの？！嘘、知らなかったの？！
Eh?! Really?! No way, you didn't know?!
そうなんです！嬉しい。
That's right! I'm so happy.
えー、そうなんだー。
Oh, I see.
そうなんです。だから私にとってもすごく思い入れのある曲で。
Yes. So it's a song with a lot of personal meaning for me.
嬉しくて、嬉しくて…
I'm just so, so happy...
よかったホロライブ入ってて！
I'm so glad I joined Hololive!
今思ったわ。やったぜ。
I just thought that now. I did it.
しかもしかも、私たちReGLOSSがデビューして、最初のエキポの時。
And also, when ReGLOSS debuted and it was the first Expo.
アキ先輩、シャルイース歌ってくださったんですよ！
Aki-senpai, you sang "Shallrys"!
そう、そうそう！その話さ、ちょっとね…
Yes, exactly! About that...
らでんちゃんが「好き」って言ってくれてたし、5周年の節目だったから「シャルイース」選んだんだ。
Raden-chan said she liked it, and it was the 5th anniversary, so I chose "Shallrys".
えー！理由の一つにらでんちゃんが好きだって言ってくれたから選んだんだよ！
Eh! One of the reasons I chose it was because you said you liked it!
えー！嬉しい！やったー！そうなんだ！
Eh! I'm so happy! Yay! Is that so!
うわー嬉しい、そうなんだ。
Wow, I'm so happy. I see.
こうやって3Dになって同じ舞台に立てて。
Becoming 3D like this and standing on the same stage.
踊ってて嬉しいです、感無量です。ありがとうございます！
I'm so happy to dance, I'm overwhelmed. Thank you!
ハグハグハグ！
Hug hug hug!
ヤニ臭くないですか？ヤニ臭くないですか？大丈夫ですか？
Do I smell like tobacco? Do I smell like tobacco? Is it okay?
まあ、若干…
Well, slightly...
うわあ！嘘嘘、いい匂い、いい匂い！大丈夫よ！
Waah! Just kidding, it's a good smell! You're fine!
よかった、よかった。ヤニ臭いの嫌だもん。
Good, good. I'd hate to smell like tobacco.
エキポの時にまさに初めてお会いしたんですよね。
We met for the first time at the Expo, didn't we?
そうだね、直接ね、会って。
That's right, meeting directly.
オンライン上では多分何回か…
Online, probably a few times...
そうだね、話したりだとかね。
Right, like talking and stuff.
あったんですけど、その時に「なんて優しい人なんだ」と思って。
We had, but at that time I thought, "What a kind person."
リハか何かの時にお隣に座らせていただいたんですよ。確かその時。
I got to sit next to you during a rehearsal or something. Yeah, that time.
なんて優しくて、太陽みたいな方なんだと思って。
I thought, "What a kind person, like the sun."
えー、そんな褒めてくれるの…ちょっともう、恋に落ちそうでした。
Eh, praising me that much... I was almost falling in love.
えー！恋？！
Eh! Love?!
でもらでんちゃんとはなんかね、今年もっと仲良くなりたいなと思って。
But with Raden-chan, I want to get even closer this year.
思ってるから、ちょっと色々さ…ついにアキロゼ解放！
I'm thinking that, so, like... finally Aki Rose unleashed!
やったー！私禁煙してよかったよみんな！
Yay! Everyone, I'm glad I quit smoking!
ヤニ臭くないしね！
And you don't smell like tobacco!
ヤニ臭くないよみんな！待ってた待ってたこの時を！
I don't smell like tobacco, everyone! I've been waiting for this!
じゃあ、今後も仲良くしてくださいませ。
Then, please continue to be friends with me.
いや、今後はもっと…
No, from now on, even more...
いっそうこのご縁を膨らませていきましょう。
Let's make this connection even stronger.
はい！やった！よろしくお願いします！
Yes! Yay! I look forward to working with you!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
奏ちゃん、おめでとうございます！
Kanade-chan, congratulations!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
改めて本日は来ていただいて本当にありがとうございました！
Thank you again so much for coming today!
またねー！ありがとう！頑張ってね！バイバーイ！
See you! Thank you! Good luck! Bye-bye!
うわあぁ！
Uwaaa!
はい、というわけでございまして、
And so,
そろそろね、皆さんに投票いただいているアンケート結果が出る頃だと思います。
it's about time for the results of the poll you all voted on to come out.
えー、アンケート結果、見て、で、ステージ移動にしにいきたいと思いまーす。
Um, I'll check the poll results and then move to the next stage.
アンケート結果見ていきましょう、こちらでーん、
Let's look at the poll results, here they are...
じゃじゃーん！
Ta-da!
どちらの花を見に行く？
スミレの花
Which flower will you go see?
Violet
なるほどね、そうなったのね。オッケー、
I see, so that's how it turned out. Okay,
じゃあ次の曲にいってきまーす！
then I'm off to the next song!
てい！
Tei!
それは九月だった
It was September
怪しい季節だった
It was a mysterious season
夕闇をドレスに変えて
Turning the twilight into a dress
君が踊れば街も踊る
If you dance, the city dances too
まるでマンハッタン・ストーリー
Just like a Manhattan story
君さえいればパラダイス
If only you're there, it's paradise
昔見たシネマのように
Like a cinema I saw long ago
恋に人生かけてみようか
Shall we bet our lives on love?
You-you-you 誘惑の摩天楼
You-you-you, the skyscraper of temptation
You-you-you 夢が花咲く
You-you-you, dreams bloom
すみれ September Love
Violet September Love
Oh-oh-oh September Dancing
明日は明日 ライララ...
Tomorrow is tomorrow, lai-la-la...
君は夢かまぼろし
Are you a dream or an illusion?
すみれ September Love
Violet September Love
Again 今夜は
Again tonight
September Dreaming
ゆらゆらゆら揺られてライララ
Swaying, swaying, swaying, lai-la-la
君は奇跡だった
You were a miracle
優しい天使だった
You were a kind angel
諦めを覚えかけてた
I was starting to learn resignation
僕の心に触れた微笑み
The smile that touched my heart
You-you-you 許されるものならば
You-you-you, if it's permitted
You-you-you 夢の続きを
You-you-you, the continuation of the dream
すみれ September Love
Violet September Love
Oh-oh-oh September Dancing
明日は明日 ライララ...
Tomorrow is tomorrow, lai-la-la...
君は君のまぼろし
You are your own illusion
すみれ September Love
Violet September Love
Again 今夜は
Again tonight
September Dreaming
ゆらゆらゆら揺られてライララ
Swaying, swaying, swaying, lai-la-la
(息を切らしながら) ということで...
(Panting) So, with that said...
ということで、えー、選ばれたのは... すみれセプテンバーラ... (咳き込む)
With that said, the one chosen was... Sumire September Love... (Coughs)
おっ、ちょっと、ああ、びっくりした！
Whoa, wait, ah, that surprised me!
びっくりした。あははは。
That gave me a shock. Hahaha.
えー、選ばれたのは、すみれセプテンバーラブでございました！
So, the one chosen was indeed "Sumire September Love"!
ありがとうございましたー！
Thank you so much!
えー、すみれの花か蓮の花か、選ばれたのはすみれの花でしたのでね。
Between the violet and the lotus, the violet was the one chosen.
もうチャット欄で予想していた方がいた通り、えー、すみれセプテンバーラブ。
Just as some of you in the chat predicted, it was "Sumire September Love."
ただ今回は一風堂さんバージョンではなく、SHAZNAさんバージョンのすみれセプテンバーラブ披露させていただきました。
However, this time I performed the SHAZNA version instead of the Ippudo version.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you!
実はアンケート結果がね...
Actually, the poll results were...
ごめん、すいませんちょっと体力なくてね。あはは。
Sorry, excuse me, I'm a bit out of breath. Hahaha.
えー、えーと、58対41くらいだったそうでございます。
It was about 58 to 41, I believe.
結構接戦ですね。
Quite a close race!
あー結構ね、差がついたんじゃないかなと思っておりますが。
I thought there might have been a bigger gap, though.
なんと、なんとここでですね...
Wait, what?! I just heard that...
なんとハッシュタグ「#らでん生誕祭2025」トレンド1位らしくて！
The hashtag "#らでん生誕祭2025" is trending at #1!
いやー！やったー！みんな！
Yeah! We did it, everyone!
トレンド1位でございます！やったー嬉しい。
It's #1! I'm so happy.
この後もね、まだまだ生誕ライブ続きますので、いっぱいっぱい感想呟いていただけると嬉しいです。
The birthday live still continues, so I'd love it if you keep tweeting your thoughts!
ということで、えー、ここで出会ったのも何かのご縁...
And so, "meeting here is also some kind of fate."
第2回目のアンケートでございます。まだありますよ、アンケートでございます。
It's time for our second poll! Yes, there's more!
じゃあ早速ね、見ていきましょう。
Let's take a look right away.
次のアンケートはこちらです！ジャジャン！
The next poll is this! Tada!
はい、えー、アンケート、「どちらに行こうか？」
Okay, the poll is "Which should we go to?"
「寄席 or 美術館」。寄席 or 美術館です。
"Yose or Art Museum." Yose or Art Museum.
まあちょっとね、あの、何かしらのヒントくれよって方がいらっしゃるかもしれないからなんですが。
Some of you might want a hint, so here it is:
新しいらでんを見たかったら寄席。
If you want to see a "new" Raden, pick Yose.
かわいいらでんを見たかったら美術館って感じでございます。
If you want to see a "cute" Raden, pick Art Museum.
さあぜひ皆さん、どっちも投票してください。
Please cast your votes!
次の曲ね、この次の曲が終わるまでに選んでください。
Please choose before the next song ends.
次の曲が終わったら締め切っちゃいますよ。
I'll close the poll once it's over!
さあということでね、えー、そんなアンケートも皆さんに答えてもらいつつなんですが。
So, while you're all voting...
次の曲はあのゲストお二人が登場します！
The next song features two special guests!
その次の曲もあのゲストが！
And the song after that features those guests too!
は、はあ...
*Panting*
それでは、ゲストパートです。どうぞ！
Alright, here is the guest segment. Please enjoy!
Go to 鎌倉DANCE 明かすよSUN
Go to Kamakura DANCE, I'll reveal it, SUN
巡る時代 おりおりLOVE
The turning eras, love in every season
ステップタップ リズムに乗って
Step tap, ride the rhythm
鎌倉STYLE!
Kamakura STYLE!
阿須賀陀 奈良平安からの 鎌倉
Asuka, Nara, Heian, and then... Kamakura!
南北朝から令和まで 鎌倉STYLE!
From the Nanboku-cho period to Reiwa... Kamakura STYLE!
いい箱作ろう いい国作ろう どっちもU Know? 超有能
1185 (Build a good box) 1192 (Build a good country) You know both? Super capable
思い詰まった時代は鎌倉 進め南北朝まで洗うわ
An era full of thoughts, it's Kamakura. Proceed, washing up to Nanboku-cho.
一所懸命 地元レペゼン 命追い回しに変幻
Giving it my all, representing the hometown. Changing forms while chasing life.
日向でスイカ ひとくちして 鎌倉STYLE!
Eating a bite of watermelon in the sun. Kamakura STYLE!
若衆 石碑 嗜んで 神社に深く肖って
Enjoying the youths and stone monuments. Deeply benefiting from the shrines.
どんな時代も僕たちは
No matter the era, we...
楽しいことがやめられない
Can't stop doing fun things!
いざ Go to 鎌倉DANCE 明かすよSUN
Now, Go to Kamakura DANCE, I'll reveal it, SUN
巡る時代 おりおりLOVE
The turning eras, love in every season
徒然なるまま Go the way 和楽器鳴らして Fly away
Follow your heart, Go the way. Play the Japanese instruments and Fly away.
超未来まで繋いでいく
Connecting all the way to the far future
Go to 鎌倉DANCE 明かすSUN
Go to Kamakura DANCE, I'll reveal it, SUN
鼻歌が聴こえたら
If you hear humming...
ステップタップ リズムに乗って
Step tap, ride the rhythm
ステップアップ 大人になって 鎌倉STYLE!
Step up, becoming an adult. Kamakura STYLE!
ドンドコドンドコ ドンドコガンガン ドドガンガン オオサレ オオサレ
Dondoko dondoko... (Traditional festival chant sounds)
右肩上がり 太鼓鳴らし どこまで行っても あの子眼差し
Rising on the right, beating the drums. No matter where I go, her gaze...
ピーヒラピーヒラ シャンシャンシャン 僕と一緒に踊りませんか？
Pii-hira pii-hira, shan shan shan. Won't you dance with me?
なんて言えない今晩も 鎌倉SHOCK!
Even tonight when I can't say it... Kamakura SHOCK!
争いごとは絶えないし 悲しいニュースも尽きないし
Conflicts never end, and sad news never stops.
こんな世界で僕たちは
In a world like this, we...
幸せなこと探していく
Will keep looking for happy things.
鎌倉STYLE!
Kamakura STYLE!
鎌倉STYLE
Kamakura STYLE
改めて、お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Once again, happy birthday!
らでんさん、お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Raden-san, happy birthday!
誰から話し始めるんだよって思ってｗ
I was wondering who'd start talking first, haha.
鎌倉ナイト 踊る時間
Kamakura Night, dancing time
いつまでも 終わらぬ夜
A night that never ends
ステップアップ 心踊れ 行くよ！
Step up, let your heart dance, here we go!
鎌倉DANCE 明かすSUN
Kamakura DANCE, until the SUN comes up
巡る時代 Only LOVE
Changing eras, Only LOVE
徒然なるまま Go the way
Following my whims, Go the way
和歌散らして Fly away
Scattering Japanese poems, Fly away
超未来まで繋いでいく
Connecting all the way to the far future
鎌倉DANCE 笑えばFUN
Kamakura DANCE, it's FUN if you laugh
恋の予感 進めよYUNG
Premonition of love, keep moving, YOUNG one
レッツダッシュ 思いのまま
Let's dash, just as you feel
鎌倉STYLE!
Kamakura STYLE!
弥生 古墳
Yayoi, Kofun
平安
Heian
鎌倉
Kamakura
南北朝 室町
Nanbokucho, Muromachi
安土桃山 江戸
Azuchi-Momoyama, Edo
明治 大正 昭和
Meiji, Taisho, Showa
平成
Heisei
令和
Reiwa
未来
Future
俺たちが作り上げていく
We're the ones who'll build it
ステップアップ リズムになって
Step up, become the rhythm
ステップアップ おとなになって
Step up, become an adult
鎌倉STYLE!
Kamakura STYLE!
というわけで！
And there we have it!
大丈夫ですか？
Are you okay?
息整えて。大丈夫ですか？
Catch your breath. Are you alright?
高坂さん、竜ヶ崎リンさんのお二人に来ていただきました！ありがとうございます！
We have Kohsaka-san and Ryuugasaki Rin-san here! Thank you for coming!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
自己紹介を高坂さんからお願いします！
Could we have introductions, starting with Kohsaka-san?
はい毎度。バーチャル音楽ユニット「MonsterZ MATE」のラップ担当で吸血鬼、高坂とはしやん。
Hello. I'm Kohsaka (Hashiyan), the vampire rapper from the virtual music unit 'MonsterZ MATE'.
ほい、ななしいんく所属、竜ヶ崎リンと申します。誕生日おめでとう！
Hey, I'm Ryuugasaki Rin from Nanashi Inc. Happy birthday!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
そしてお呼びいただきありがとうございます！
And thank you for inviting us!
えー、なぜこのお二人をお呼びしたかと申しますと...
Well, as for why I invited these two...
去年、2024年の3月10日のラジオで「Vレポ」というラジオがあったんですが...
Last year, on March 10, 2024, there was a radio show called 'V-Repo'...
そこで共演させていただいて...
We performed together there...
あの、カットされたところではあるんですけど...
And although it was in a part that was cut...
いつか、ね、一緒に歌いたいです！ってそこで言ったので私が。
I said then that I wanted to sing together with them someday.
私のわがままをお二人が今日叶えに来てくださいました。本当にありがとうございます！
These two came to fulfill my selfish wish today. Thank you so much!
いいえ、そんな。ありがたいね。
Oh, not at all. It's a pleasure.
誠実な、我々と一緒に歌いたいだなんてありがたいよ。
It's an honor that someone as sincere as you would want to sing with us.
俺らみてぇなカスみてぇなねｗ ゴミみてぇな奴らとｗ
With trash like us, haha. With total garbage like us.
もう、音楽の大先輩ですから！
You're both my great seniors in music!
とっても一緒に歌えて楽しくて嬉しいです。ありがとうございます！
I'm so happy and had so much fun singing together. Thank you!
こちらこそ。ありがとうございます！
Likewise. Thank you!
で、この鎌倉スタイルって曲もね、すごくノリの良い曲で。
And this song, 'Kamakura Style', is such a groovy track.
一人で歌うのも良いけど、なんか誰かと一緒に歌いたいな、みたいなところがあって。
Singing it alone is fine, but I really felt like I wanted to sing it with someone.
ちょっとドキドキしながらお声がけさせていただいたんですけども。
I was a bit nervous when I reached out to you.
心良く来ていただきました！本当にありがとうございます！
And you were kind enough to come! Thank you so much!
楽しかった。感謝が止まんねぇ。ありがとうございます。
It was fun. I can't thank you enough. Thank you.
マジで楽しかった。
It really was fun.
ただリハでね、間奏の部分でぐるぐる回るのをやってたんですけど...
Though, in rehearsal, we were spinning around during the interlude...
まぁらでんさんが死んでしまうということで、本番はやめようとｗ
But since Raden-san was about to die, we decided not to do it for the show, lol.
そうですねｗ 息が上がって上がってね、らでんの。
Exactly, haha. Raden's breath was just gone.
ずっと楽しそうだからｗ
Because she seemed to be having so much fun, haha.
楽しかったし、なんかあの、リハの最中に高坂さんが私に...
It was fun, and during the rehearsal, Kohsaka-san said to me...
「あれ、そんなキャラだっけ？」ってｗ
'Wait, was that your character?' haha.
「あれ、らでんちゃんそんなキャラだっけ？」ってｗ
'Wait, Raden-chan, was that really your character?' haha.
初めて会った時さ、俺はもう、「あぁなんて聡明な方なんだろう」と。
When we first met, I thought, 'Oh, what an intelligent person'.
高坂君にお前とは正反対だな、って言われたのめっちゃ覚えてる。
I clearly remember you telling me, 'She's the exact opposite of you, Kohsaka'.
今日めちゃくちゃ口エンジンかかってるからｗ
Her mouth-engine is running at full speed today, haha.
僕よりマジ元気。
She's seriously more energetic than me.
びっくりしちゃった。
I was surprised.
でもおかげさまでリハーサルからずっと楽しくて。
But thanks to that, it's been fun since the rehearsal.
ステージの上でも楽しかった、めちゃくちゃ。
It was so much fun being on stage, too.
いや嬉しい、ありがとうございます！
I'm so glad, thank you!
なんか、宣伝していきますか？
So, do you have anything to promote?
雑っ！ｗ 急に雑！ｗ
That's so blunt! Suddenly so blunt, haha!
まぁ我々もね、活動してるんですけど、まぁ、なんか...
Well, we're active too, so, well...
XなりYouTubeチャンネルなり見ていただければ。
If you could check out our X or YouTube channels.
今日はもう、らでんさんおめでとうございます、と。ライブもまだまだ続くので。
For today, just a big congrats to Raden-san. The live show is still going on.
まぁ僕らから言うこともありませんが、最後までぜひ皆さんも盛り上がって行っていただければと思います。
Well, we don't have much more to say, but we hope you all keep the energy up until the end.
改めてらでんさん誕生日おめでとう！
Once again, Raden-san, happy birthday!
高坂さん、リンさん、今日は本当にありがとうございました！
Kohsaka-san, Rin-san, thank you so much for today!
バイバイ！ ありがとうございました！
Bye-bye! Thank you very much!
お二人とも、ありがとうございましたー！
Thank you both so much!
次の曲もなんとゲストがいらっしゃいます！
The next song also features guests!
それでは、どうぞ！
So, here it is!
Ladies and Gentlemen!
お江戸わらびーそ！
Oedo Wara-diso!
行きは良い良い、帰りは笑い...
Going is pleasant, returning is laughter...
Ladies and Gentlemen!
Please enjoy the follow Oedo Wara-diso!
いよいよいいかい？帰りもわっはっはっ！
笑いながらも通れんせ
Are you ready? Coming back is a big laugh!
Laughing as you pass through,
笑われながらもわっはっはっ！
While being laughed at, laugh it off!
あー うららレンタルのかわ
Ah, the lovely rental skin,
メンタルの皮剥ぎましょう
Let's peel off the mental skin.
ほら見なよ歌穂めら まったぬけは わっはっはっ！
Look, Kaho-mera, a complete escape, wah-ha-ha!
変貌はクレイよ ならばレレレ
The transformation is clay, then le-le-le,
変貌はツメ研いだよう
Looks like the transformation sharpened its claws.
ほら見な舞台指から漏れるぶら不和笑いあらら
Look at the stage, disharmony leaking from the fingers, oh my laugh.
ウレキシを照明せよ
非現実世界へ出世も宝石もないが
Illuminate the joy!
In the surreal world, no fame or jewels, but...
戯れれるなら生まれ落ちの正体は
If we can play, our true identity from birth is,
I know where you're from アンダーグラソウゲンキョウ
I know where you're from, Underground Sogenkyo.
ダブダブ
Dabudabu
わっはっはっせーは ダブダブダ
Wah-ha-ha say, Dabudabuda!
絡まったらっせーは リアルねのダボ
Entangled, it's a double of the real world.
キャラはあらわ ダボらませらばらっと出す生まれ変わるわ
The character is exposed, making it double, popping out, being reborn.
わっはっはっせーは ダブダブダ
Wah-ha-ha say, Dabudabuda!
絡まったぼせーが 揺れるエゴエド
The entangled shadow is the swaying Ego Edo.
笑いきり遊ばせ 暴からば再武屋 わっはっはっはー！
Laugh all you want, if we rampage, it's Saibu-ya, wah-ha-ha-ha!
ののなかちょ みかちょめかちょ
なかちょなかちょ うぇいかちょ えぇかちょ
Nononaka-cho, Mikachome-kacho,
Nakacho-nakacho, Wey-kacho, Ee-kacho!
転がりゃ止まれんな 戻れんな
忘れんな 忘れんな 罪連打 ガチャガチャ
Once you roll, you can't stop or go back!
Don't forget, don't forget, a combo of sins, Gacha-Gacha!
狂おしけりゃまぁいいじゃん バラバラと都
If it's crazy, that's fine, the capital in pieces.
轟々ととろは恨めしや百目 偶像あれ晴れ！
Roaring like a dragon, the hundred-eyed grudge, let the idol shine!
ダブダブ生まれあんな言葉で憎まれは誉れだと悟る眼鏡の裏
Dabudabu born, being hated by those words is an honor, I realize behind the glasses.
危険な顔ぶれ晒されたら眠る死屍
When the dangerous faces are exposed, the corpses sleep.
もっと盛り上げていきましょう！
Let's heat things up even more!
ウォエーオー ウォオエーオー
Whoa-eh-oh! Whoa-oh-eh-oh!
絡まった変境 暴れなや挑戦状
Entangled borderland, rampage on, it's a challenge!
はにかんだ転生はわかる 握るぜほいほいほい
I understand the shy reincarnation, I'll grasp it, hoi-hoi-hoi!
Ladies and gentlemen, please enjoy the paradise of WWW.
薔薇色だ我は地はダブ
Rose-colored am I, the ground is Double,
ガタカブキバから零れるワルワルワラ
Laughter spilling from the rattling Kabuki fangs, waru-waru-wara!
ダブダブ
Dabudabu
わっはっはっせーは ダブダブダ
Wah-ha-ha say, Dabudabuda!
絡まったらっせーは リアルねのダボ
Entangled, it's a double of the real world.
キャラはキャラだ あばかすざらになんどだって生まれ変わるなら
A character is just a character, reborn as many times as it takes in the rough abacus.
やっぱりせーは ダブダブダ
After all, say, Dabudabuda!
絡まったぼせーが 揺れるエゴエド
The entangled shadow is the swaying Ego Edo.
笑いきり遊ばせ さらば終わり輪廻や わっはっはっはー！
Laugh all you want, farewell to the end, it's Samsara, wah-ha-ha-ha!
ラスト！ ダブダブダブダブ
Last one! Dabudabudabudabu!
はい！ 薔薇色だ我は地はダブ
Yes! Rose-colored am I, the ground is Double,
ガタカブキバから零れるワルワルワラ
Laughter spilling from the rattling Kabuki fangs, waru-waru-wara!
はー！いえーい！
Hah! Yay!
お邪魔してまーす！おめでとうー！
Sorry for intruding! Congratulations!
おめでとうだよー！
Congrats!
ありがとうー！
Thank you!
息止めてもらって。ふー、ふー、ふー、ふー。
I need to catch my breath... Phew, phew, phew, phew.
というわけで、というわけで、えー、なんとゲスト3組目は、
So, so... for our third set of guests,
ヒメヒナのお二人に来ていただきましたー！
We have the two of HIMEHINA joining us!
いえーい！
Yay!
お邪魔しておりますー！ご挨拶しますか？
Thanks for having us! Shall we introduce ourselves?
しましょう！
Let's do it!
いくよ、せーの！
Here we go, one, two...!
はろー、田中ヒメです！
Hello, I'm Tanaka Hime!
鈴木ヒナです！
I'm Suzuki Hina!
二人合わせて、ヒメヒナです！
And together, we are HIMEHINA!
よろしくー！いえーい！
Nice to meet you! Yay!
おめでたー、おめでたー！
Happy birthday, happy birthday!
ほ、本物...
The... the real deal...
あれ、ご本人？ご本人？
Wait, are you the real one? The real one?
あ、なすなす、それなに、それなに
Ah, Nasunasu, what's that? What's that?
落ちゆく花びらを表現しました
I was expressing falling flower petals.
みんなでやっとこうか、めでたいしね
Let's all do it, it's a happy occasion after all.
めでてー、めでてー。
本当にめでたいのかこれ？分からんｗ
Congrats, congrats.
Is this really celebratory? I have no idea lol.
はい、ということでございまして、えー、
Right, so, anyway,
『WWW』を、ダブダブを、一緒に歌わせていただきました！
We sang 'WWW' (Dabudabu) together!
ありがとうー！ずっとこの曲が大好きで！
Thank you! I've always loved this song!
嬉しいー！
I'm so happy!
大好きー！
We love it too!
ねー、一緒にできてよかったー！嬉しくて！
Right? I'm so glad we could do this! I'm so happy!
でね、あの、伏線もちゃんとあったんですよね。
And you know, there was actually a foreshadowing.
一度コラボにお呼びいただきまして。去年コラボかな？
You invited me to a collab once. Was it last year?
コラボね、去年12月？
The collab, last December?
11月末ぐらいだね
Around the end of November, I think.
ぐらいだね、そこで『WWW』が好きだからと言ってたのが...
Right around then. Back then, I said I liked 'WWW'...
嬉しい！一緒に歌いたいって言ってたんですが...
I'm so happy! I said I wanted to sing together...
その伏線が今日回収されました！
And that foreshadowing was paid off today!
わー！嬉しい！
Wow! I'm so happy!
どうだったかな？
How was it?
いや、すごかった！
No, it was amazing!
振付もすごいしっかり覚えてこれてさ。
You remembered the choreography really well.
歌もめっちゃかっこいい。
The singing was also really cool.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
ちょっとね、ダンスはね、ちょこちょこミスってるので、ぜひアーカイブでご確認下さい。
Regarding the dance, I made some mistakes here and there, so please check the archive.
あー！間違い探しだ！間違い探ししてるんで。
Ah! It's spot the difference! I'm playing spot the difference.
始まる前もさ、端っこで一生懸命練習しててね。
Even before it started, you were practicing hard in the corner.
我々も「ほぉ〜」て。
We were like, "Whoa!"
盛り上がってて。
Getting all excited.
本当に贅沢すぎる、ダンスの先生が...
It's really too luxurious, the dance teacher...
いやいやいや、本当にありがとうございます。
No no no, thank you very much.
3人で踊るの最高に楽しかった！楽しかったね！
Dancing as a trio was so much fun! It was great!
いや、なんかこの3人とちょっと久々になるのかな？
Well, it's been a while since the three of us were together, right?
まぁ、ちょっとね。久々だね。久々だけどね。
Well, a bit. It's been a while. It's been a while, but...
でも我々と言えばもうさ...
But speaking of us...
はい！
Yes!
ミリオン同期だよ！ミリオン同期！
We're Million-sync gen-mates! Million-sync!
100万人おめでとう！おめでとう！
Congratulations on 1 million! Congrats!
待って、これちょっと待って、1、1、1作って。
Wait, wait a minute, make a 1, 1, 1.
8だね。180だ。180だ、それ。
That's an 8. It's 180. That's 180.
あ、180万人。よいしょ！百万ポインツ！百万ポインツ！
Ah, 1.8 million people. There we go! Million points! Million points!
めでたく同じくらいの時期にね、100万人を達成しまして。
Happily, we reached 1 million around the same time.
ミリオン同期ということで。
So we're "Million-sync gen-mates."
素晴らしいですね。
That's wonderful.
今後もね、仲良くしていただきたいんですけども、よろしくお願いします。
I hope we can continue to get along, please look forward to it.
よろしくお願いします。
Please look forward to it.
でもまだね、なんか、あれ？あれあれ？
But still, like, huh? Huh, huh?
なんかある気がするけどな。もっとやりたいしね。
I feel like there's more. I want to do more.
わー！匂わせ入りました！
Whoa! The teasing has started!
あれ？あれ？
Huh? Huh?
まだまだお楽しみがあったらいいなーってね。あるのかな？あるのかな？
It would be nice if there's still more to enjoy. Is there? Is there?
もっともっといろいろやってこう。そうだね。やってこう。
Let's do more and more various things. Right. Let's do it.
やっていきましょう。
Let's do it.
ツアーもお疲れ様！
Good job on the tour!
あー、ありがとう！来てくれて、もう超嬉しかった！ありがとう！
Ah, thank you! I was so happy you came! Thank you!
もう1曲目バーって始まった瞬間からボロ泣き。
I was bawling from the moment the first song started.
いや、そう。すごい好きって言ってくれるから。
Yeah, exactly. Because you say you like it so much.
もうこっちも気合入るよ、本当に。
It really gets me fired up too, really.
もう大好きなんんで、ツアーの最初でも泣き、100万人達成でも泣き。
I love it so much, so I cried at the start of the tour, and at the 1 million milestone.
立派なジョシでございます。
She's a fine lady.
本当にありがとう。
Truly, thank you.
ハイパイも100万で歌ってくれて。絶対歌おうと思ってたんで。
You also sang 'High Five' at the 1 million mark. I was determined to sing it.
ありがとう。ありがとうございます。
Thank you. Thank you very much.
あんな素敵なタイミングでね、お祝いできて嬉しいね。
I'm happy we could celebrate at such a wonderful timing.
嬉しい。そんな中で、あの100万人達成緊急配信をされてたじゃないですか。
Happy. And in the middle of that, you were doing the emergency stream for the 1 million milestone, right?
我々も見たいと思って、あの、タグとかで、#姫ヒナ100万人 で付けて投稿したら...
We wanted to watch it, so we posted with the tag #HimeHina1M...
配信中に「なんか、らでんちゃんが呟いてくれてる！」って言って。
And during the stream, they said "Hey, Raden-chan is tweeting!"
認知されてる、恥ずかしい。
I've been recognized, it's embarrassing.
コラボしてるのに認知もないだろ。
We're collaborating, so of course you're recognized.
そっか。そうそうそうですよ。ファンのふりして教えてくれてね。
Right. That's true. You told them while pretending to be a fan.
そうそうそう。いや、嬉しい。
Exactly. No, I'm happy.
改めておめでとうございます。
Congratulations once again.
ありがとう。そしておめでとうございます。
Thank you. And congratulations to you too.
おめでとう連鎖。よろしくお願いします。
A chain of congratulations. Please look forward to it.
はい、ということでございまして、姫ヒナ様のお二人に来ていただきました。本日は本当にありがとうございました！
Yes, and so, we had the two members of HimeHina here. Thank you so much for today!
ありがとう！おめでとうだよ！ありがとうございます！
Thank you! Congratulations! Thank you very much!
じゃあ行きますか。
Shall we go then?
はい、はけましょう。よし。ありがとうみんな、バイバイね！
Yes, let's leave. Alright. Thank you everyone, bye bye!
え、別々？え、あー！バイバイ！
Wait, separately? Eh, ah! Bye bye!
はい、ということでございましてね。ちょっとだいぶただのファンになっちゃったんですけど後半。
Yes, and so. I ended up becoming just a fan for the latter half.
お二人とも、本当にありがとうございました！
Thank you both so much!
さて、皆さん。そろそろですね、アンケートの結果が出たところだと思います。
Now, everyone. I think the results of the survey are about to come out.
ドキドキのアンケート結果、見ていこうと思います。
Let's take a look at the nerve-wracking survey results.
アンケート結果はこちら、ドン！
The survey results are here, bam!
さあ皆さん、らでん生誕祭2025、楽しんでますか？みんなー！
Now everyone, are you enjoying Raden's Birthday Festival 2025? Everyone!
さあ、今から披露する曲は、皆さんのアンケートで美術館が多かったので...
Now, the song I'm about to perform is, because "Museum" was the top choice in your survey...
美術館にまつわる曲、歌っちゃいますよ。
I'm going to sing a song related to museums.
今流れてるこのイントロの曲なんですけど、みんな「この曲なんじゃないか」「あの曲なんじゃないか」って予想してくれてて。
It's this song with the intro currently playing, everyone was guessing "Is it this song?" or "Is it that song?"
それ見るのもとっても楽しいですし、あと何だかトレンドが日本と世界1位ということで、ありがとうございます！
Watching that is really fun, and also, thank you for trending #1 in Japan and the world!
ピピカソ
Pipikaso
ピピピピピピピカソも ダ・ヴィンチも
Pi-Pi-Pi-Pi-Pi-Picasso and Da Vinci too
好きなものだけ 自分で決める
I'll decide only what I like by myself
ダリ ロートレック セザンヌ ゴッホ 太郎 もちろんに 兄貴 シャガール ロダン ミケランジェロ マネは法
Dali, Lautrec, Cezanne, Gogh, Taro, of course Big Brother, Chagall, Rodin, Michelangelo, Manet is the law
ガウディ モネ ダ・ヴィンチ
Gaudi, Monet, Da Vinci,
セザンヌ ゴッホ 写楽 ムンク
Cezanne, Gogh, Sharaku, Munch,
カミュ ドラクロワ ミレー キュビスム モナリザも
Camus, Delacroix, Millet, Cubism, and even Mona Lisa
いいか悪いかは自分で決める
Whether it's good or bad, I'll decide for myself
どうして空は青いのか
Why is the sky blue?
どうして赤くて黒いのか
Why is it red and black?
当たり前のことなんて何にもないんだ
There's no such thing as "it's only natural"
ビ・ビ・ビ・ビ・ピカソも ダ・ヴィンチも
Bi-bi-bi-bi-Picasso, and Da Vinci too,
いいか悪いかは自分で決める
Whether it's good or bad, I'll decide for myself
おもいのままに生きなはれ
Live as you please
今をお大事に生きなはれ
Cherish the present moment
誰にでもあって自分を磨く
Everyone has it, polish yourself
一つしかない自分を磨く
Polish your one and only self
誰にでもあって自分を磨く
Everyone has it, polish yourself
一つしかない自分も磨く
Polish your one and only self too
常住坐臥 常住坐臥 常住坐臥 常住坐臥
Always, always, always, always
はい！ここで楽曲の途中ですが、宣伝があります！
Yes! We're in the middle of a song, but I have an announcement!
じゃん！なんと現在、箱根ガラスの森美術館にて、
Tada! Currently, at the Hakone Museum of Glass and Forest,
お子さま用音声ガイドを私、儒烏風亭らでんと
I, Juufuutei Raden, and...
ホロライブの先輩の博衣こより先輩の二人で担当させていただいてます！
...Hololive senior Hakui Koyori-senpai are in charge of the kids' audio guide!
お子さま用音声ガイドとは言っても、
Even though it's called a "kids' audio guide,"
大人の方が聴いてもめちゃめちゃ面白い音声ガイドとなっております！
it's a very interesting guide for adults to listen to as well!
期間は7月13日までとなっております。
The period is until July 13th.
ぜひとも皆様、箱根に足をお運びください！
Everyone, please visit Hakone!
何卒、何卒、何卒よろしくお願いします！
Please, please, please check it out!
常住坐臥 常住坐臥 常住坐臥 常住坐臥
Always, always, always, always
ロートレック マティス アンリ・ルソー ゴッホ 北斎
Lautrec, Matisse, Henri Rousseau, Gogh, Hokusai,
モディリアーニ シャガール ロダン ミケランジェロ マネ ウォーホル
Modigliani, Chagall, Rodin, Michelangelo, Manet, Warhol,
ガウディ モネ ダ・ヴィンチ セザンヌ ゴッホ
Gaudi, Monet, Da Vinci, Cezanne, Gogh,
写楽 ムンク カミュ ドラクロワ ミレー キュビスム
Sharaku, Munch, Camus, Delacroix, Millet, Cubism
ビ・ビ・ビ・ビ・ピカソも ダ・ヴィンチも
Bi-bi-bi-bi-Picasso, and Da Vinci too,
好きなものだけ自分で決める
I'll decide on my favorite things for myself
どうして海は広いのか
Why is the sea so wide?
どうして浅くて深いのか
Why is it shallow and deep?
一つだけの事なんて何にもないんだ
There's no such thing as only one thing
常住坐臥 常住坐臥 常住坐臥 常住坐臥
Always, always, always, always
いいか悪いかは自分で決める
Whether it's good or bad, I'll decide for myself
おもいのままに生きなはれ
Live as you please
もっと大きく生きなはれ
Live a bigger life
どこにでもあって自分を磨く
Everywhere, polish yourself
ここにしかない自分を磨く
Polish your one-of-a-kind self
どこにでもあって自分も磨く
Everywhere, polish yourself too
ここにしかない自分を磨く
Polish your one-of-a-kind self
どこにでもあって自分で磨く
Everywhere, polish it yourself
ここにしかない自分が磨く
Your one-of-a-kind self will polish it
はーい！というわけで皆さん、アンケートのご協力ありがとうございました！
Alright! So everyone, thank you for your cooperation in the poll!
選ばれた曲は、えー、52%！美術館でビ・ピカソでございました！
The chosen song was, uh, with 52%, "Bi Picasso" at the Museum!
ありがとうございましたー！
Thank you very much!
4万7000票くらい入ってたそうです、ありがとうございます。
It seems there were about 47,000 votes. Thank you.
でね、曲の冒頭で、あの、あれしたんですけど、
And, you know, at the beginning of the song, I mentioned that...
なんと #らでん生誕祭2025
Wait, #RadenBirthday2025
日本とそれからトレンドの1位なんでございますって！皆さん！
is #1 on trending in Japan and globally! Everyone!
信じられないな...。まあ、こんな締まらなさも
I can't believe it... Well, this lack of composure
らでんぽっちゃらでんぽいのでね。
is also very Raden-like.
え、で、ちなみに、今回のアンケートで
Oh, and by the way, about the song
選ばれなかった曲はどうするんじゃいというお話でございますが、
that wasn't chosen in this poll,
なんと、選ばれなかった曲に関しては、このあと、
well, regarding the unselected song,
面源のメンバー限定のアンコールライブで、
in the member-only encore live after this,
えー、選ばれなかった方の曲を、
I'm planning to perform the one that wasn't chosen
まあアナザー...なんとかみたいな感じでやろうと思います！
as an "Another [version/part]"!
なのでね、ちょっと気になる、気になるなーという方は、
So, if you're curious about it,
今のうちにメンバーシップに入っていただけるととっても嬉しいです！
I'd be very happy if you'd join the membership now!
よろしくお願いします！
Please do!
さあ、このあともまだまだ生誕祭続きます。このあとゲストパートでございます！
Well, the birthday celebration continues. Next up is the guest part!
それでは、どうぞ！
And here it is!
はいはいでグッバイでバイバイ
Bye-bye with a high-high and a goodbye
アストロノート
Astronaut
話を聞いてほしいな
I want you to hear my story
君からしたら平穏なことだろうけど
It might seem peaceful to you, but...
メッセージは手書きにしてよ
Please write the message by hand
言葉は宙に浮いてしまうから
Because words tend to float away into space
形に残る方が綺麗だから
Because things that take shape are more beautiful
まだまだ行こう
Let's keep going further
現在の視界は良好
Current visibility is clear
自由落下の
Our journey of
旅を続けよう
free fall continues
ひとりぼっちで
The two of us alone
ヘルツを合わせた二人
our frequencies aligned
それって幸せだ
That's what happiness is
バイバイでグッバイでバイバイ いつか会う日まで
Bye-bye with a goodbye, until the day we meet again
それまで残る僕らの魔法 イェイイェー
Until then, our magic remains, yeah yeah
会いたい反対の反対 そこが終点だ
The opposite of the opposite of 'I want to see you,' that's the end point
いまだに僕ら歌っている イェイイェー
We are still singing even now, yeah yeah
たいしたこともないのに
Even though it's nothing important
笑えてしまうことがある
sometimes we just end up laughing
きっと、そんなんでいいのさ
I'm sure that's just fine
別れは青かった
Our parting was green
メッセージは言葉にしてよ
Please put the message into words
君の声を覚えていたいから
Because I want to remember your voice
形のあるものは有限だから
Because physical things are finite
どこまで行こうかなんて言いながらさ
While saying things like, "I wonder how far we should go?"
僕らみな分かっていた 岐路に立ってしまうこと
We all knew that we would eventually reach a crossroads
ひとりぼっちと分かれ道は似てるけど
Being alone and a fork in the road are similar
また交わるから
but we'll meet again
バイバイでグッバイでバイバイ 全て群青だ
Bye-bye with a goodbye, everything is ultramarine
駆け抜けてから思い知った幼さ
The childishness I realized after running through it all
バイバイ反対の反対 そこが終点だ
Bye-bye, opposite of the opposite, that's the end point
いずれ、僕らにも訪れるだろうから
Because it will eventually come for us as well
孤独な旅が続いていく
A lonely journey continues
周回軌道で出会えた僕らは逸れるだろう
We who met in orbit will likely drift apart
声が変わって 背が高くなって
Even if our voices change, we grow taller
見えるものしか信じなくなっても
and we only believe what we can see
夢を語るんだろう
we'll probably still talk about our dreams
中身のない話も素敵だから
Because even empty conversations are wonderful
まだまだ行こう
Let's keep going
一人で行こう
Let's go alone
バイバイでグッバイ Days
Bye-bye with a goodbye Days
バイバイでグッバイでバイバイ これでサヨナラだ
Bye-bye with a goodbye, this is goodbye
ついに解ける僕らの魔法
Our magic is finally breaking
会いたい反対は会いたい それでいいんだよ
The opposite of 'I want to see you' is 'I want to see you,' and that's okay
退屈さえも愛していた イェイイェー
I even loved the boredom, yeah yeah
たいしたこともないのに
Even though it's nothing important
ずっと笑えてしまう日々のこと
the days that always made me laugh
そっとしまっておくのさ
I'll gently tuck them away
僕らは青かった
We were so young
手探りで夢を見る
Groping for dreams
何もない ただ信じて
There's nothing there, just believe
宇宙までが遠いほど
The further away the heavens are
片道切符を求めて
Searching for a one-way ticket
Wow...
気付いてくれる人がいる
There's someone who notices me
誰も見向きもしなくても
Even if no one else gives me a second look
肩を組んで笑ってきた
We've walked with arms around each other, laughing
僕らはきっと負けない
We surely won't lose
Wow...
I don't want anything
いつだって今が
The present is always...
Wow...
常にスタートライン
...the starting line
Music is everything
遥かなユニバース
A distant universe
Wow...
走れ STAR TRAIN
Run, STAR TRAIN
線路のない道をゆく
Going down a road with no tracks
想像を超えて進みたい
I want to move beyond my imagination
歯車のように噛み合う
Meshing together like gears
力は一人じゃ伝わらない
Power can't be conveyed by one person alone
Wow...
I don't want anything
いつだって今が
The present is always...
Wow...
常にスタートライン
...the starting line
Music is everything
遥かなユニバース
A distant universe
Wow...
走れ STAR TRAIN
Run, STAR TRAIN
Wow...
I don't want anything
いつだって今が
The present is always...
Wow...
常にスタートライン
...the starting line
Music is everything
遥かなユニバース
A distant universe
Wow...
走れ STAR TRAIN
Run, STAR TRAIN
I don't want anything
いつだって今が
The present is always...
Wow...
常にスタートライン
...the starting line
Music is everything
遥かなユニバース
A distant universe
Wow...
走れ STAR TRAIN
Run, STAR TRAIN
Wow...
せーの！お誕生日おめでとう！
One, two! Happy Birthday!
ということで、らでん生誕祭2025、
And so, for Raden Birthday Festival 2025,
ReGLOSSメンバーの5人に来てもらいました！
the five members of ReGLOSS have joined us!
改めましてにはなりますが、自己紹介お願いします。青くんから。
It's a re-introduction, but please introduce yourselves. Starting from Ao-kun.
はい！らでんちゃんちの隣の隣のちょっと斜め前くらいに住んでる
Yes! I'm Hiiragi Ao, who lives next door to next door,
火威青です。よろしくお願いします。
slightly diagonally in front of Raden-chan's house. Nice to meet you.
近いの？遠いの？
Is that close or far?
おでんちゃんのクラスの隣のクラスの
I'm Otonose Kanade, a friend from the class next to
ちょっと知り合いのクラスメイトか分からないぐらいの友達な音乃瀬奏でーす！
Oden-chan's class, who's a classmate she might not even know is an acquaintance!
他人？他人じゃん！
A stranger? You're a stranger!
えー、らでんの行きつけのお店の店主の
Uh, I'm Todoroki Hajime, the daughter of a
友達の友達の娘の轟はじめです！
friend of a friend of the owner of Raden's favorite shop!
一番遠いかも。
That might be the farthest one.
らでんちゃんがよく行くお酒を飲む場所で、
I'm Ichijou Ririka, who was sitting four seats away
隣の隣の隣の隣の席に座ってた一条莉々華です！
at the place where Raden-chan often goes for drinks!
面白いな、そんな遠いと...
That's interesting, from so far away...
ということでございましてね、
And so,
今回のライブテーマ「ここで出会ったのも何かのご縁」。
the theme of this live is "It's some kind of fate that we met here."
やはりね、出会いのご縁と言えばこのReGLOSSのメンバーということで。
After all, when it comes to the fate of meeting people, it's the ReGLOSS members.
やっぱりね、一番最初「Our Bright Parade」も
After all, at the very beginning, "Our Bright Parade"
5人で歌わせていただきました。楽しかったね。
was sung by the five of us. It was fun, wasn't it?
楽しかったー！
It was fun!
ねー。振りもね、みんなで練習してね、覚えたりなんかいたしまして。
Right. We practiced the choreography together and memorized it.
で、今聞いていただいたのは「Start Line」という曲なんですけど、
And the song you just heard was "Start Line,"
この曲ね、ちょっとね...
but this song...
うわー、みんな真似するやん！
Wow, everyone's copying the moves!
この曲ね、あの、らでんが以前からすごく好きな曲で、
This song is one that I've liked for a long time,
ね、歌詞が良いんですよね。
and the lyrics are great.
「いつだってここがスタートライン」って。
"Anytime is a start line."
やっぱそれはね、ちょっとReGLOSSメンバーとも重なるところがあったりなんかしちゃって。
It kind of overlaps with the ReGLOSS members in some ways.
やっぱ5人で歌いたいなと思って、
I really wanted to sing it with the five of us,
ありがたいことに、そして贅沢なことにですね、
and thankfully—and quite luxuriously—
このライブでReGLOSSメンバー5人で歌う曲2曲歌わせていただきました。
we were able to sing two songs with all five members in this live.
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
よー、呼んでくれてありがとー！
Yay, thank you for inviting us!
さあ、ということでございまして、もう残すところあと一曲となりました。
Now then, there's only one song left.
最後、ちょっと、らでんがしかも一人で、生で、やるっていうので
For the last one, I'm going to do it solo and live,
ちょっとあのめちゃくちゃ緊張してるので、
so I'm incredibly nervous.
ちょっと一緒に曲振りをしていただいてもよろしいですか？
Could you help me introduce the song?
もちろんだよ！
Of course!
もちろん！お供するわよ！
Of course! I'll accompany you!
じゃあ、時間が、時間が！いきましょう皆さん。
Then, the time, the time! Let's go everyone.
せーの！
Ready, go!
どうぞ！
Please enjoy!
晴る
作詞・作曲：n-buna
Haru
Lyrics & Composition: n-buna
あなたは風のように
You are like the wind
目を閉じては夕暮れ
Closing my eyes, it's dusk
何を思っているんだろうか
I wonder what you are thinking
まぶたを開いていた
My eyelids were open
あなたの目はビードロ
Your eyes are like vidro
少しだけ春の匂いかした
A faint scent of spring lingered
晴れに晴れ、花よ咲け
Fair and sunny, flowers bloom
咲いて晴れのせ
Blooming in the fair weather
降りやめば雨でさえ
If it stops falling, even the rain
あなたを飾る晴る
Is the brightness that adorns you
胸を打つ音よ鳴れ
The sound that strikes my heart, ring out
僕ら晴風
We are the clear wind
あの雲も越えて行け
Go beyond those clouds
遠くまで遠くまで
Far away, far away
あなたは晴れ模様に
You are in a sunny mood
目を閉じては青色
Closing my eyes, it's blue
何が悲しいのだろうか
I wonder what is sad
まぶたを開いている
My eyelids are open
あなたの目にビードロ
In your eyes, vidro
今少し雨の匂いかした
A faint scent of rain lingered just now
泣きに泣け、空よ泣け
Cry and cry, oh sky cry
泣いて雨のせ
Cry in the rain
降りしきる雨でさえ
Even the pouring rain
雲の上では晴る
Above the clouds, it's brightness
土を打つ音よ鳴れ
The sound that strikes the earth, ring out
僕ら晴れ雨
We are the sunny rain
あの海も越えて行け
Go beyond that sea
遠くまで遠くまで
Far away, far away
通り雨、草なびかせて
A passing shower, making the grass sway
羊雲 あれも春のせい
Altocumulus clouds, those are also because of spring
風の音を胸に春のせい
The sound of the wind in my heart, because of spring
春を待つ
Waiting for spring
晴れに晴れ 空よ咲け
Bright and clear, oh sky, bloom
咲いて春のせい
Bloom, because of spring
降りやめば 雨でさえ
When it stops falling, even the rain...
あなたを飾る春
...is a spring that adorns you
胸を打つ 音奏で
Striking my heart, playing a sound
僕ら春風
We are the spring breeze
不如帰 春の風
Little cuckoo, spring breeze
さあ この歌よ 投げ
Now, cast this song
晴れに晴れ 花よ咲け
Bright and clear, oh flowers, bloom
咲いて春のせい
Bloom, because of spring
あの雲も越えて行け
Go even beyond those clouds
遠く まだ 遠くまで
Far away, even further away
はい！ということで、
Yes! So,
最後の曲は『春』聴いていただきました。
the last song was "Haru".
どうだったでしょうか？
How did you like it?
実は、この曲はね、ホロライブDEV_ISのね、
ReGLOSSのチャンネルでも...
Actually, for this song, on the hololive DEV_IS
ReGLOSS channel...
ReGLOSSの5人でカバー動画を出してる曲となっております。
all five members of ReGLOSS have released a cover video.
聴いたことあるよって方も、
Whether you've heard it before,
あ、それ初耳だよって方もぜひね
聴いてくれるととっても嬉しいです。
or it's your first time, I'd be very happy
if you'd listen to it.
『春』ありがとうございましたー！
Thank you for "Haru"!
えーそれではですね、ここで、グッズ紹介をしたいと思うんですが...
Well then, I'd like to introduce the goods here...
今回のね、ライブ、至る所で、
In today's live, in various places—
至る所って言っても2回なんですけど...
well, just twice...
二択が出てきましたね。
two choices came up.
皆様にいろんな選んでもらうというところを重視したんですが...
I emphasized having everyone choose various things...
今回なんとグッズも2種類二択あります！
And this time, there are also two types of goods to choose from!
ちょっと今回グッズたくさんあるので駆け足でいきますよ！
There are many items, so I'll go through them quickly!
まずはこちら、じゃじゃーん！
First, this one! Ta-da!
儒烏風亭らでん 誕生日記念 2025
Juufuutei Raden Birthday Celebration 2025
はい、儒烏風亭らでん誕生日記念2025
フルセットの内容がこんな感じとなっております！
Yes, here is the content of the Juufuutei Raden
Birthday Celebration 2025 Full Set!
では気になる所でしょうから
You're probably curious,
一つずつご紹介いたしますね。一つ目お願いします。
so I'll introduce them one by one. First one, please.
ちょっと一服キャンバスアート
Just a Quick Break Canvas Art
はいこちら、『ちょっと一服キャンバスアート』でございます。
Yes, this is the "Just a Quick Break Canvas Art".
イラストはサムネイルを書いてくださった、
みつきさなぎ先生です。ありがとうございます！
The illustration is by Mitsuki Sanagi-sensei,
who also drew the thumbnail. Thank you!
ね、このレトロな雰囲気いいでしょう？
Doesn't this retro atmosphere look great?
すごいいいと思わない？
Don't you think it's wonderful?
この立ててるやつ、これね、木のやつ、
あの『イーゼル』って言うんですが、
This thing holding it up, this wooden one—
it's called an "easel".
この立てるやつイーゼルもついててお家で飾れます。
It comes with this easel so you can display it at home.
サイズは15cm×22cmくらいです。
The size is about 15cm x 22cm.
二つ目は、こちらでん、でぃりん！
The second one is this! *Sound effect*
SNS風アクリルキーホルダー
SNS-Style Acrylic Key Holder
はい、SNS風アクリルキーホルダー。
Yes, an SNS-style acrylic key holder.
イラストはきのこシリーズの動画でおなじみ、
ぱかくん三世先生に描いていただきました。
The illustration was drawn by Pakakun III-sensei,
who is well-known for the mushroom series videos.
お出かけに行った際に一緒にこれとね、一緒に写真撮ってもらって、
When you go out, please take a photo with this,
ぜひハッシュタグ『行ったよらでんちゃん』で
投稿してみてください。
and post it with the hashtag #RadenChanWasThere.
三つ目は、こちらでじゃじゃん！
Third is this! Ta-da!
らでんのラジオ風ポーチ
Raden's Radio-Style Pouch
らでんのラジオ風ポーチ。
アンティークなラジオ風のデザインポーチとなっております。
Raden's radio-style pouch.
It's a pouch with an antique radio-style design.
中身が見えるクリア窓となっておりまして、
ホロライブフレンズ with u 儒烏風亭らでんを、
It has a clear window so you can see inside, and a
"hololive friends with u" Juufuutei Raden plushie...
こ、縦に入れてね、
いい感じに入るくらいのサイズ感となっております。
...fits perfectly when placed vertically.
そしてお次はこちらでん、でぃりん！
はい、印籠風キーホルダーでございます。
And next is this! *Sound effect*
Yes, an inro-style key holder.
印籠風キーホルダー
Inro-Style Key Holder
皆様あの印籠ご存知でしょうか？
Do you all know what an inro is?
蓋がね、ぱかって開閉可能なやつで、
The lid can be popped open, you know—
あの、あれ、あの『この紋所が目に入らぬか』のやつです。
蓋が開閉可能でございます。中は空洞ですよ。
it's like that thing from "Can you not see this crest?!".
The lid is openable. It's hollow inside.
ぜひ皆様も、この印籠風キーホルダーで
『この紋所が目に入らぬかごっこ』に使ってください。
Please use this inro-style key holder
to play "Can you not see this crest?!".
お次はこちらでん、じゃじゃん！
Next is this! Ta-da!
ASMRボイス 『散歩のすゝめボイス』
ASMR Voice: "Guide to Taking a Walk Voice"
はい、今回ボイスASMRとなっております。
タイトルは『散歩のすゝめボイス』。台本は自分で考えました！
Yes, this time, it's an ASMR voice.
The title is "Guide to Taking a Walk Voice". I wrote the script myself!
そして、フルセットの購入特典あります。
フルセット購入特典はこちらでん、じゃじゃん！
And there's a full set purchase bonus.
The bonus is this! Ta-da!
フルセット購入特典
Full Set Purchase Bonus
直筆サイン入りポストカードでございます！
それから特典のASMRボイス『散歩よすゝめボイス』が入っております。
It's a hand-signed postcard! It also includes the
bonus ASMR voice, "Guide to Taking a Walk Voice".
今回サインに関しては無制限でございます。
There's no limit on the number of signed items this time.
焦らずにご購入いただければと思います。
頑張って書きますよ！頑張ります！
So please take your time to purchase.
I'll do my best to sign them all! I'll work hard!
さらに、フルセット特典がまだあります。うん。
Furthermore, there's another full set bonus. Yes.
さらにフルセット特典として、昨年の9月から販売されました
As an additional full set bonus, one card that has
ホロライブオフィシャルカードゲームで使用できるカードが1枚つきます。
been on sale since last September for the hololive Official
Card Game will be included.
ございます。
...there is.
カードはホロライブプロダクションオフィシャルショップで購入された方のみ対象となります。
The card is only available for those who purchase from the hololive production OFFICIAL SHOP.
特典につくのは、推しをアピールできるキーカード「推しホロメンカード」です。
The bonus is a key card called "Oshi Holomen Card" that lets you show off your favorite.
カードの詳細や遊び方については、ホームページにてご確認ください。
For card details and how to play, please check the official website.
カードは日本語版のみとなりますので、ご了承ください。
Please note that the card is only available in Japanese.
さ、こちらがですね、誕生日記念グッズだったんですが...
So, those were the birthday celebration goods, but...
さあ、2種類目いきましょうか！2択目でございます。それがこちらです、ジャン！
Now, let's move on to the second type! It's the second option. Here it is! Ta-da!
はい、儒烏風亭らでん「きのこダンスグッズ」フルセットの内容がこんな感じ。
Yes, here's the content of the Juufuutei Raden "Kinoko Dance Goods" full set.
ひとつずつご紹介しますね。まずは、こちらです。
I'll introduce them one by one. First, this one.
はい、「ぬいぐるみキーホルダー まいたけダンスver.」。
Yes, the "Plushie Keyholder: Maitake Dance ver."
きのこシリーズの「ぱわくん三世」さんのイラストのキーホルダーでございます。
It's a keyholder featuring an illustration by Pawa-kun III from the mushroom series.
まいたけ、まいたけ、ぐるぐるしておりますね。
Maitake, maitake, it's spinning around.
お次は、こちらです、ジャン！
Next is this! Ta-da!
「缶バッジ」。こちらも「ぱわくん三世」さんのイラスト。
"Tin Badges." These also feature illustrations by Pawa-kun III.
こちら、あの、ランダムではないです！ランダムじゃないです。
These aren't random! Not random.
色々なきのこダンスのショート動画のイラストが缶バッジになりました。
Illustrations from various Mushroom Dance short videos have become tin badges.
まいたけ、しめじ、しいたけ、まつたけ、エリンギの5種類となっております。
There are five types: maitake, shimeji, shiitake, matsutake, and king oyster mushroom.
お次は、こちらです、ジャン！
Next is this! Ta-da!
「マスキングテープ」。まいたけダンスのアニメーションをイメージしたマスキングテープ2種類入ってます。
"Masking Tape." It comes with two types of masking tape inspired by the Maitake Dance animation.
これね、搬入の時とか便利です。
This is useful for when you're moving things and such.
そして、フルセット購入特典がこちらにもあります。どうぞ、ジャン！
And there's a full set purchase bonus for this too. Here it is! Ta-da!
はい、ぱわくん三世さんのイラスト、ぐるぐるしてる「ステッカー」でございます。
Yes, it's a spinning sticker with an illustration by Pawa-kun III.
という感じで、なんとグッズが同時に2つも出ております。
So, amazingly, two sets of goods are being released at the same time.
今回ね、みんなにこう選んでいただく楽しみがあったと思うんですが...
I think there's the fun of choosing which one you like this time...
今回もね、ちょっと自分が好きなほうはどっちかなーってたくさん悩んでください。
Please think hard about which one you prefer.
もちろんね、あの、どっちも買うこともできますので、よろしくお願いします。
Of course, you can also buy both, so please consider it.
はい、ということで、らでん生誕祭2025、いかがでしたでしょうか。
All right, so, how did you like Raden's Birthday Festival 2025?
この日のためにね、もう歌とダンスといっぱい練習してきました。
I practiced singing and dancing a lot for this day.
よかったらね、ハッシュタグ「#らでん生誕祭2025」で感想つぶやいてくださると、とっても嬉しいです。
I'd be very happy if you'd tweet your thoughts with the hashtag "#RadenSeitansai2025".
どうぞよろしくお願いします。
Thank you very much.
さて、この後ですね、21時30分、21時30分から...
Now, after this, from 21:30, 21:30...
メンバーシップ限定のアンコールライブもございます。
There will also be a membership-only encore live.
アンケートで選ばれなかったほうの曲を披露させていただきますので、そちらもどうぞよろしくお願いいたします。
I'll be performing the song that wasn't chosen in the poll, so please check that out too.
ショップはね、21時10分にオープンします。ショップ21時10分オープン。
The shop opens at 21:10. Shop opens at 21:10.
アンコールライブが30分からメン限であります。よろしくお願いします。
The encore live will start at 21:30 for members only. Please join us.
それでは、あ、もうオープンしたっぽいですね。あ、ごめんなさい、もうオープンしました。すみません。
Well, oh, it looks like it's already open. Ah, sorry, it's already open now. Excuse me.
それではですね、皆様、メン限の皆様はこの後21時30分にまたお会いしましょう。
Well then, everyone, I'll see you members later at 21:30.
ここでお別れの方、見ていただいて本当にありがとうございました。
To those leaving here, thank you so much for watching.
それでは皆様、本日は本当にありがとうございました。
Everyone, thank you so much for today.
それでは、さようならでーす！ありがとう！
Well then, goodbye! Thank you!